You know who's gotta be the bravest person in the Marvel Universe?
Qui est le plus courageux des habitants de l‘univers Marvel ?
Whoever has to give She-Hulk a bikini wax.
Celle qui fait le maillot à Miss Hulk.
You wanna talk brave?
Qui est courageux ?
How about Captain America's undocumented Mexican gardener?
Le jardinier mexicain sans papiers de Captain America.
He's not braver than whoever uses the bathroom after the Thing.
Il l‘est moins que celui qui va aux toilettes après la Chose.
As usual, you're all wrong.
Comme d'habitude, vous avez tous tort.
Bravest person in the Marvel Universe is the doctor...
Le plus courageux, c‘est le médecin
...who gives Wolverine his prostate exam.
qui examine la prostate de Wolverine.
What about the guy who gets a prostate exam from Wolverine?
Et celui qui se fait examiner la prostate par Wolverine ?
Now you're just being silly.
Tu racontes n‘importe quoi.
Wolverine's never displayed interest in helping others prevent prostate cancer.
Wolverine n‘ajamais aidé personne à dépister un cancer dela prostate.
Hello?
Allô ?
Yes, the elevator's out of order. You'll have to use the stairs.
Oui, l‘ascenseur est en panne. Prenez les escaliers.
Of course you can.
Vous pouvez le faire.
Pizza dates back to the 16th century...
La pizza date du 16ème siècle
...while the first elevator was not installed until 1852.
et le premier ascenseur n‘a pas été installé avant 1852.
That means that for over 300 years...
Pendant plus de 300 ans,
...people carried pizzas upstairs.
les gens ont monté les pizzas à pied.
Be part of that proud tradition.
Participez à cette fière tradition.
I'll go get Penny while that guy spits on our food.
Je vais chercher Penny pendant qu'il crache sur notre repas.
Do you think they gave Wolverine an adamantium prostate?
Ils ont donné à Wolverine une prostate en adamantium ?
That's a stupid question.
C‘est une question idiote.
We're having a conversation about probing the heinies of superheroes.
On parle de passer une sonde dans la tuyauterie des superhéros.
There are no stupid questions.
Il n‘y a pas de questions idiotes.
-Yes? -Oh. Uh....
Oui ?
ls Penny here?
Penny est-elie ici ?
You're Leonard, right?
Tu es Leonard ?
Damn, it's good to finally meet you, son.
Je suis content de te rencontrer enfin.
Okay, I think a bit of context here might help.
Un peu de contexte m'aiderait à mieux comprendre.
Oh, hey, Leonard. I see you met my dad.
Salut. Tu as rencontré mon père.
Oh, good. Context.
D‘accord. C‘est le contexte.
Come in, buddy. Take a load off.
Entre. Viens t'asseoir.
Oh, Dad, Leonard can't stay. He just dropped by to say hello.
Leonard ne peut pas rester. Il passaitjuste dire bonjour.
Thanks for stopping by, sweetie. I'll see you later.
Merci d'être passé, chéri. A plus tard.
Bye.
Au revoir.
That was odd.
C'était étrange.
Are you sure you have enough comics?
Tu as pris assez de comics ?
You're monitoring the telescope for 12 hours, and by my estimate...
Tu vas passer 12 heures sur le télescope,
...you've only selected seven hours of reading material.
et tu n'as sélectionné que 7 heures de lecture.
That's even factoring in your difficulty...
J'ai pris en compte tes difficultés
...in parsing American comic-book idioms like "Bamf" and "Snikt."
à assimiler des mots étrangers comme Bang et Schtong.
Is that racist? It feels racist.
C‘est moi ou c'était raciste ?
Don't be oversensitive. He's calling you illiterate, not your race.
Ne sois pas si susceptible. C‘est toi qu'il traite d'illettré, pas ta race.
I don't need more comics. Howard's gonna stop by.
J'ai assez de comics. Howard va passer me voir.
We'll play Intergalactic Battleship and Indian Monopoly.
On jouera àla Bataille lntersidérale et au Monopoly indien.
I don't care for novelty editions of Monopoly.
Je n'aime pas les nouvelles éditions du Monopoly.
I prefer the classics, regular and Klingon.
Je préfère les traditionnelles, comme le classique et le klingon.
Actually, Indian Monopoly's just like regular.
Le Monopoly indien est comme le classique.
Except the money's in rupees, instead of hotels you build call centers...
Sauf qu'on joue avec des roupies, qu'on construit des centres d‘appel
...and when you pick a Chance card you might die of dysentery.
et qu'en tirant une carte Chance, on peut mourir de dysenterie.
Oh, just FYI, that was racist.
Ça c'était raciste.
You'll never guess what happened.
Devinez ce qui s‘est passé.
You went out in the hallway, stumbled into a portal...
Tu es sorti dans le couloir, tu es tombé dans un portail
...which brought you 5000 years into the future...
qui t‘a amené 5 000 ans dans le futur
...where you took advantage of the technology to build a time machine.
où tu as construit une machine à remonter le temps.
Now you're back to bring us all to 7010, where we are transported...
Tu es revenu nous chercher pour nous transporter en 7010
...to work at the Thinkatorium by telepathically controlled flying dolphins?
pour travailler au Pensorium avec des dauphins télépathes ?
Penny kissed me.
Penny m‘a embrassé.
Well, who would ever guess that?
On n'auraitjamais pu le deviner.
-What kind of a kiss? -A big kiss, on the mouth.
- Embrassé comment ? - Sur la bouche.
Is it possible that she was going for your cheek...
Est-il possible qu'elle visait lajoue,
...and you moved and she accidentally got lip?
tu as bougé et elle a eu la lèvre par accident ?
That happens with me and my mom all the time.
Ça m'arrive tout le temps avec ma mère.
She introduced me to her father...
Elle m‘a présenté son père,
...kissed me and then shut the door in my face.
m‘a embrassé et m‘a fermé la porte au nez.
She was trying to send you a message.
Elle t‘a envoyé un message.
-You think? HOWARD: Yeah.
Tu crois ?
"This man is not my father, I'm being held hostage...
Cet homme n‘est pas mon père, je suis retenue en otage,
...so I'm gonna do something insane in the hopes that you'll call 911."
alors je fais un truc dingue pour que tu appelles les secours.
Penny kissing me is not insane. She used to kiss me all the time.
Ce n‘est pas dingue. Elle m'embrassait tout le temps.
Einstein defined insanity as doing the same thing over and over again...
Pour Einstein, la folie était la répétition d‘une même chose
...and expecting different results.
dans l'espoir d'un résultat différent.
By that standard, Penny is cuckoo for Cocoa Puffs.
D‘après cette définition, Penny est folie à lier.
I'm just saying, it felt like it may have meant something.
Ça voulait peut-être dire quelque chose.
Oh, this takes me back. Leonard obsessing about Penny.
Encore cette Vieille rengaine. L‘obsession de Leonard pour Penny.
Don't get me wrong, I love your new stuff...
J'aime tes nouveaux titres,
...but once in a while, it's nice to hear the hits.
mais j'aime bien réécouter tes Vieux tubes.
That one always makes me laugh.
Ça me fait toujours rire.
Why do I bother talking to you people?
Pourquoi je m‘obstine à vous parler ?
If it will make you feel better, we rarely listen.
Si ça peut te consoler, on écoute rarement.
-Can I talk to you out here for a sec? -Yeah, sure.
- Je peux te parler ? - Bien sûr.
I'm starting to think we're never going to see that pizza.
Je commence à croire qu'on ne verrajamais cette pizza.
You're probably wondering what that was about.
Tu dois te demander pourquoi j'ai fait ça.
What? The kissing and everything?
Quoi ? Le baiser ?
No, women do that to me all the time.
Non, les femmes se jettent sur moi tout le temps.
The thing is, I kind of told my father we got back together again.
J'ai dit à mon père qu'on s‘était remis ensemble.
What? Why?
Pourquoi ?
You're the first guy he's ever really approved of.
Tu es mon premier copain qu'il apprécie.
You're a scientist who went to college and you don't have a neck tattoo...
Tu as été en fac de sciences, tu n'as pas de tatouage dans le cou
...or outstanding warrants, or--
ou un mandat contre toi, ou…
Or a baby.
Ou un bébé.
What kind of guys did you used to go outwith?
Avec quel genre de types es-tu sortie ?
Just guys.
Des types.
When I told him we split up, he was heartbroken.
Quand on a rompu, il a eu le cœur brisé.
He kept bugging me, "How's Leonard? "Why can't you get back together?
Il m‘a harcelée : ”Pourquoi tu ne retournes pas avec Leonard ?"
I bet Leonard never tipped a cow over on himself."
"Leonard ne s‘estjamais retrouvé sous une vache."
So to get him off my back, I told him we worked things out.
Pour qu'il me lâche, je lui ai dit qu'on s‘était réconciliés.
Really?
Vraiment ?
How-- How did we manage that?
Comment a-t-on fait ?
-What? -I mean, did you apologize?
- Quoi ? - Tu t'es excusée ?
Did you have to woo me?
Tu as dû me faire du charme ?
Get over yourself. lwhistled, you came running.
Redescends sur terre. J'ai sifflé et tu as accouru.
-Yeah, no, I don't think so. -Okay, why are you arguing about this?
- Non, ça m‘étonnerait. - Pourquoi tu veux débattre de ça ?
I'm saying, if we fake got back together...
Si on s‘est réconciliés pour de faux,
-...that's totally not how it fake happened. -Oh.
ça ne s‘est pas passé comme ça pour de faux.
Will you please just play along until my dad leaves?
Tu peux jouer le jeu jusqu'au départ de mon père ?
Hold on, you actually want me to deceive your father...
Tu veux que je mente à ton père
...with some sort of sham play-acting and kissing?
en jouant la comédie et en t'embrassant ?
Because I'm good with that.
Ça ne me dérange pas.
WYATT: Penny, you out here?
Penny, tu es la ?
Come on, honey, not in front of my dad.
Arrête, chéri. Pas devant mon père.
Relax, I've seen you do a lot worse with a lot stupider.
Je t'ai vu faire bien pire avec des types bien plus bêtes.
See? He doesn't mind.
Ça ne le gène pas.
I'm taking your gal out for dinner. You wannajoin us?
J'emmène ta copine dîner. Tu veux venir ?
Oh, Dad, that's nice, but Leonard has to work.
C‘est gentil, mais Leonard a du travail.
-Right, Leonard? -I do, I have to work.
- N‘est-ce pas ? - Oui, j'ai du travail.
But I'm gonna blow that off to spend the evening with my sweetie and her father...
Mais je peux tout envoyer valser pour être avec ma chérie et son père.
...because it's just the kind of boyfriend I am.
Je suis ce genre de petit ami.
-Come here, you. -Oh....
Viens la, toi.
-C-7. -Miss.
- C-7. - Raté.
How could that be a miss? C-6 was a hit, C-8 was a hit.
Raté ? Je t'ai touché en C-6 et en C-8.
Part of your starship has to be on C-7.
Ton vaisseau spatial est forcément en C-1.
Not if it has a hole in the middle.
Pas s'il a un trou au milieu.
What kind of spaceship has a hole in the middle?
Quel genre de vaisseau spatial a un trou au milieu ?
A Romulan battle bagel?
Un bagel de combat romulien ?
BERNADETTE: Knock, knock.
Toc, toc.
Oh, great, you made it. Come on in.
Super, tu as pu venir. Entré.
I invited her.
Je l'ai invitée.
So where's the telescope?
Où est le télescope ?
Well, it's in Hawaii, but Raj controls it from here.
A Hawaï, mais Raj le contrôle d'ici.
He's hoping to see Epsilon Eridani dim...
Il espère voir une éclipse d‘Epsilon Eridani,
...which would be evidence of a planet orbiting it.
ce qui prouverait qu‘une planète gravite autour.
So we just sit and stare at the screen, waiting for something to happen?
On reste assis à fixer l‘écran en attendant qu'il se passe un truc ?
I did it with you when we rented The Notebook.
C‘est ce que j'ai fait avec toi quand on a loué N'oubliejamais.
Yes, Gena Rowlands is a treasure.
Oui, Gena Rowlands est une grande actrice.
You better open up that bottle of wine or I'm gonna end up with swimmer's ear.
Va ouvrir la vin avant que je finisse avec une otite.
Excuse me, I can't be drinking.
Je ne peux pas boire.
I'm about to make an important scientific discovery here.
Je suis sur le point de faire une grande découverte scientifique.
-How do you know that? -Well, he was Italian.
- Comment le sais-tu ? - Il était italien.
It's a reasonable assumption.
C‘est une hypothèse plausible.
Dude, can you even open your mouth without spewing a cultural stereotype?
Tu peux l'ouvrir sans balancer un stéréotype culturel ?
I'm sorry, Galileo drank diet Sprite.
Pardon, Galilée buvait du Sprite light.
Look, you're my best friend, she's my girlfriend, you should bond.
Tu es mon ami, elle est ma copine. Vous allez vous entendre.
You know, like you and my mom did.
Comme toi avec ma mére.
Your mom creeps the hell out of me.
Ta mère me fout les jetons.
Yes, but she's stopped calling you Slumdog Millionaire.
Oui, mais elle a arrêté de t'appeler Slumdog Millionaire.
I do appreciate that.
J'apprécie beaucoup.
Here we go.
Tenez.
Oh, well, I'd like to propose a toast.
J'aimerais qu'on lève nos verres.
To science and friendship.
Ala science et à l‘amitié.
Hold on. Wait.
Attendez.
-No, it's okay, go ahead. -What?
- Non, c‘est bon. Buvez. - Quoi ?
l was working with penicillin-resistant gonorrhea in the lab today...
J'ai travaillé sur une souche de blennorragie aujourd'hui,
...and l was just trying to remember if I washed my hands.
etj'essayais de me rappeler si je m‘étais lavé les mains.
-Thanks for the steak, Wyatt. -My pleasure.
- Merci pour le repas, Wyatt. - De rien.
Nice to have dinner with a boyfriend of Penny's that knows how to use a napkin.
C‘est agréable de dîner avec un ami
So not funny, Dad.
Ce n‘est pas drôle, papa.
Let me tell you about this one genius. This fella Donnie.
Laisse—moi te parle de ce génie. Il s'appelait Donnie.
Will you please let it go?
Tu peux arréter ?
Donnie was gonna make millions turning farm waste into biofuel...
Il allait devenir riche en créant du biocarburant avec du fumier
...and selling it to the government.
et en le vendant au gouvernement.
-A lot of people are doing that. -Oh, see?
- Un tas de gens font ça. - Tu vois ?
But all Donnie did was mix pig poop with water...
Donnie mélangeait du purin avec de l‘eau
...and pump it into his mom's Camry.
et le mettait dans la Toyota de sa mère.
Yeah, that's great. It's a funny story, moving on.
Très drôle. On passe à autre chose.
Donnie was a rocket scientist...
C‘était un pur génie comparé à celui
...compared to that boy who wanted to get beer pong into the Olympics.
qui voulait faire du bière-pong une épreuve olympique.
-What was his name? -Curtis.
- Il s'appelait comment ? - Curtis.
-And I'm pretty sure he was joking. -Well, I don't know.
- Je suis sûre qu'il plaisantait. - Je ne sais pas.
That petition looked real to me.
Cette pétition était bien réelle.
Okay, I think this ends the ex-boyfriend portion of our evening.
Fin dela conversation sur les anciens petits amis.
Well, I'm just glad you finally found yourself a keeper.
Je suis content que tu aies trouvé un bon parti.
Thanks, Wyatt.
Merci, Wyatt.
I'm a keeper.
Je suis un bon parti.
You wanna come in for a nightcap?
Tu veux boire un dernier verre ?
Dad, he'd love to, but Leonard has to work in the morning.
Il aimerait beaucoup, mais Leonard travaille demain matin.
-Maybe I could go in a little late. -No, no, no, you can't.
- Je pourrais commencer plus tard. - Non.
Your career is far too important.
Ta carrière est bien trop importante.
Behind every man is a nagging woman who won't let him have any fun, right?
Derrière chaque homme se cache une femme rabat—joie.
Don't I know it.
A qui le dites-vous ?
-Well, good night, son. -Good night, Wyatt.
- Bonne nuit. - Bonne nuit, Wyatt.
-Oh, good night, honey. -Good night.
- Bonne nuit, chérie. - Bonne nuit.
I love you.
Je t‘aime.
I love you too. Heh, heh.
Je t'aime aussi.
Oh, friggety-frak. Not this again.
Nom d'un Borg. Pas encore.
Three, four, five, pass go...
Trois, quatre, cinq, case départ,
...get 2000 rupees, six, seven--
je reçois 2 000 roupies, six, sept...
Whoops! Can't go any further, there's a sacred cow in my way.
Je ne peux pas aller plus loin. Une vache sacrée me bloque.
Tell your boyfriend to cool it with the cow jokes.
Dis—lui d‘arrêter les blagues sur les vaches.
It won't help. Once he finds ajoke he likes, he sticks with it.
Inutile. Quand il trouve une blague qui lui plait, il ne la lâche plus.
-Like his haircut material. -Oh, right.
- Comme la blague des cheveux. - Oui.
-"Did you get your hair cut?" -"No, I got them all cut."
- "Tu t'es coupé les cheveux ?" - ”Non, je les ai coupés en quatre."
Which is still so funny.
Ca reste très drôle.
When you go to a Chinese restaurant, he gets the same fortune in his cookie.
Au restaurant chinois, il a toujours le même message dans son biscuit.
Right. "Help, I'm a prisoner in a Chinese fortune-cookie factory."
"A l‘aide, je suis prisonnier dans une usine de biscuits chinois."
Okay, I think that's enough about me.
Assez parlé de moi.
He's right. Let's make fun of his mother.
Il a raison. Moquons-nous de sa mère.
[IMITATING HOWARD'S MOTHER] "Howard, come rub my feet.
"Howard, Viens me masser les pieds, mes cors me font un mal de chien."
[IMITATING HOWARD'S MOTHER] "Howard, help me out of the tub.
"Howard, sors—moi de la baignoire, je suis encore coincée."
Coming.
J‘arrive.
Hey, love bug.
Salut, mon lapin.
Shut up.
La ferme.
You know what I've been doing for the last hour?
Tu sais ce que je fais depuis une heure ?
Dreamily doodling "Mrs. Leonard Hofstadter" in a notebook?
Tu gribouilles en rêvassant ”Mme Leonard Hofstadter" ?
Listening to my father go on about what a great guy you are.
J'écoute mon père en train de faire ton éloge.
You gotta admit, I'm delightful.
Avoue-le, je suis charmant.
Why are you making this so difficult?
Pourquoi rends-tu tout si difficile ?
-lt's not difficult for me, I'm having fun. -Leonard.
- Ce n‘est pas difficile, je m'amuse. - Leonard.
What do you want me to do?
Que veux-tu que je fasse ?
-Do you wanna tell him we're broken up? -No.
- Tu veux lui dire qu'on a rompu ? - Non.
-Then what do you want? -I don't know.
- Que veux-tu ? - Je l‘ignore.
Don't you think that's something you should have figured out?
Tu n'aurais pas dû y réfléchir avant de débarquer ici ?
Maybe.
Peut—être.
Leonard, Penny, excellent.
Leonard, Penny, parfait.
I'd like to say I'm very happy that you're back together...
Je suis très heureux que vous soyez remis ensemble,
...and if I can figure out a way to do so and sound sincere, I will.
et si je trouve un moyen de le dire avec sincérité, je le ferai.
In the meantime, I'd like to go over some changes to the Roommate Agreement...
Examinons les changements apportés au contrat de colocation
...specifically to address Penny's annoying personal habits.
concernant spécifiquement les manies dérangeantes de Penny.
Oh, my God. What personal habits?
Mon Dieu. Quelles manies ?
l have a list.
J'ai fait une liste.
FYI, overuse of the phrase "Oh, my God" is Number 12.
L‘usage abusif de ”Mon Dieu" Vient en douzième place.
Sheldon, you don't have to do this, because Leonard and l are no--
Tu n'es pas obligé de faire ça, car Leonard et moi…
-You sure you wanna include him in this? -lnclude me in what?
- Tu veux l‘impliquer ? - M‘impliquer dans quoi ?
Is there a plot afoot? I'll have no truck with plots.
Un complot se fomente-t-il ? Je ne veux rien savoir.
No, you're right. No, there's no plots, no trucks, no feet.
Non, tu as raison. Pas de complot, pas de froment.
So, what other annoying habits shall we discuss?
De quelles autres manies doit-on parler ?
We don't discuss anything.
On ne va parler de rien.
Leonard is the signatory to the Roommate Agreement...
Leonard est le signataire du contrat de colocation.
...as such, he bears responsibility for all your infractions and must pay all fines.
Il est responsable de tes infractions et doit payer les amendes.
-Fines? -Yes.
- Des amendes ? - Oui.
If Penny's spending nights here again, you'll need to set up an escrow account.
Si Penny revient dormir ici, il va te falloir un compte bloqué.
Hello, Hawaii.
Bonjour, Hawaï.
This is Dr. Koothrappali in Pasadena.
Ici le Dr Koothrappali de Pasadena.
I'd like you to reposition the telescope, please.
J'aimerais que vous repositionniez le télescope.
Scarlett Johansson's house.
Sur la maison de Scarlett Johansson.
I'm kidding, Hawaii. Mahalo.
Je plaisante, Hawaï. Mahalo.
It might have been a mistake to open that second bottle of wine.
C‘était peut-être une erreur d'ouvrir une deuxième bouteille.
Well, live and learn.
Ça servira de leçon.
You think this planet you're looking for has an atmosphere that supports life?
L'atmosphère de cette planète pourrait-elie accueillir la vie ?
Maybe.
Peut—être.
If it did, I'd be famous. I'd be on the cover of magazines.
Si c‘est le cas, je serai célèbre. Je serai dans tous les magazines.
And then instead of living alone in my tiny apartment, I'd have a big mansion.
Au lieu de Vivre seul dans mon studio, j‘aurai un manoir.
-Well, that sounds great. -It is.
- C‘est génial. - Oui.
If you like wandering around a big empty house with no one to love you.
Si on aime errer seul sans personne qui vous aime.
-We'd come visit you. -No, you wouldn't.
- On viendra te voir. - Non.
You'd be intimidated by my wealth and fame.
Ma gloire et ma richesse vous intimideront.
My only friends would be my genetically engineered monkey butler...
Mes amis seront mon singe valet génétiquement modifié
...and the little people I hired to be my living chess set.
et les nains engagés pour être mes pièces d'échec.
He's taking a turn to the dark side.
Il est tombé du côté obscur.
-Oh, hold on, he could come back. -What's the point of everything?
- Attends, il peut revenir. - A quoi bon ?
Nope. He's gone.
Non. Il est foutu.
It's more than a year since I've kissed a girl.
Je n'ai pas embrassé de fille depuis plus d'un an.
What about that hookup at Comic-Con you told me about?
Et la fille que tu as draguée au salon des comics ?
Grow up, I was lying, I lie all the time. Nobody wants to kiss me.
J'ai menti. Je mens tout le temps. Personne ne veut m'embrasser.
You poor, poor thing.
Pauvre garçon.
Raj, you have to know, you're a wonderful man.
Raj, tu es un homme merveilleux.
There are a lot of girls out there who wanna kiss you.
Beaucoup de filles ont envie de t'embrasser.
-Where? -You just have to look.
- Où ? - Regarde autour de toi.
Well,this was fun.
C‘était marrant.
Oh, I think I got a nibble.
J'ai une touche.
Oh, be careful. Give him some line.
Allez—y doucement. Laissez—lui de la ligne.
Okay, now reel him in.
Vous pouvez le remonter maintenant.
Oh, look at that baby. They're really biting, huh?
Regarde—moi cette belle prise. Ils mordent vraiment.
Yeah, they do that when you set it on "easy."
Ça mord quand on est en mode facile.
Oh, that's me.
C‘est mon téléphone.
Hello? Oh, hi, sweetie.
Allô ? Bonjour, chérie.
I got up early and didn't wanna wake you...
Je me suis levé tôt. Pour ne pas te réveiller,
...so I went out for coffee, ran into Leonard on the way back.
je suis sorti prendre un café etj'ai croisé Leonard.
Guess what. We're fishing.
On est en train de pêcher.
Yeah, right here on his couch.
Sur son canapé.
Hey, baby, I love you.
Bonjour, ma chérie. Je t‘aime.
That's Leonard. He says he loves you.
C‘est Leonard. Il dit qu'il t‘aime.
What?
Quoi ?
The whole thing's bull squirt, huh?
Ce n‘était que des salades ?
Well, that's very disappointing.
Je suis très déçu.
Bye.
Au revoir.
Oh, hey, there's something I've been meaning to tell you.
Il y a quelque chose que je voulais vous dire.
I can't believe you would lie to me.
Comment as-tu pu me mentir ?
-I did not wanna be a part of this. -l'll get to you in a minute.
- Je n‘étais pas d‘accord. - Je m‘occuperai de toi après.
My daughter thinks I don't love her enough to support her...
Ma fille pense que je ne l'aime pas assez
...no matter what choices she makes.
pour la soutenir dans ses choix.
-l'm sorry, Daddy-- -Let me finish.
- Je suis désolée... - Laisse—moi finir.
I thought we were past the days when you'd pull the wool over my eyes.
Je pensais que c‘était fini l'époque où tu m‘embobinais.
Telling me the baggie in your underwear drawer is potpourri.
Tu me disais que le sachet dans ta lingerie était un pot—pourri.
And the pee stick in your bathroom is to check for diabetes.
Et que le test urinaire était pour le diabète.
I know. I'm sorry.
Je sais. Je suis désolée.
I respect your right to make your own decisions...
Je respecte ton droit à prendre tes décisions.
...but all I ask is you respect me enough to be honest about them.
Je veux que tu me respectes assez pour être honnête.
You're right. From now on, I will tell you the truth.
Tu as raison. Je ne te mentirai plus.
Thank you. Now go and put some clothes on.
Merci. Va t‘habiller.
We'll grab a bite before I head for the airport.
On va manger avant d‘aller à l‘aéroport.
-Okay. -Now you--
A ton tour.
-He had nothing to do-- Okay. -Keep walking.
- Il n‘a rien... - File.
Please, please, please don't give up on her.
S'il te plaît, n‘abandonne pas.
What?
Quoi ?
I can't go back to the skateboard idiots, the white rappers...
Fini les skateboardeurs débiles, les rappeurs blancs
...and all the sweaty dumb-asses with their backwards hats.
et les abrutis en sueur avec leurs casquettes à l‘envers.
Gee, I don't know if it's in the cards, sir.
J'ignore si c‘est ce que les cartes ont prévu.
Then stack the deck.
Alors mélange le jeu.
Cheat, lie, I don't care.
Triche, mens, ça m‘est égal.
I want grandkids and I want them to grow up in a house without wheels.
Je veux des petits enfants, et pas dans une maison sur roues.
-l'll give it a shot. -Thank you.
- Je vais tenter le coup. - Merci.
Now, I'm gonna do something here to help you along.
Je vais faire un truc pour t'aider.
-Excuse me? -Just don't panic.
- Pardon ? - Ne panique pas.
[YELLING] Now get your sorry, lying ass out of my face...
Toi et ta gueule de menteur, vous dégagez,
...and make sure I never see it again.
etje ne veux plus jamais vous revoir.
Oh, the reverse-psychology thing. I see, that's very clever.
La psychologie inversée. C‘est très malin.
[IN NORMAL VOICE] Don't yap. Just get out.
Arrête de jacter. Tire-toi.
I'll friend you on Facebook.
Je vous mettrai en ami sur Facebook.
Oh, there you are.
Tu es la.
Just so you know, I was up all night...
Je n'ai pas dormi de la nuit,
...but I've finally completed the Penny-specific section...
mais j'ai enfin terminé d'écrire la clause Penny
...of the new Roommate Agreement.
du nouveau contrat de colocation.
Yeah? Well, not necessary, we broke up again.
Ce n‘est plus la peine. On a encore rompu.
Do you even think about other people, Leonard?
Penses-tu parfois aux autres, Leonard ?
Do you?
Ça t'arrive ?
Hey. Oh, how did it go last night?
Salut. Ça s‘est bien passé hier soir ?
Oh, you know. Same old, same old.
Tu sais, la routine.
Looked through a telescope, saw some stars, big whoop.
J'ai regardé dans un télescope, j'ai vu des étoiles, youpi.
Really? You waited months for time with that telescope.
Tu as attendu des mois pour accèder à ce télescope.
-What happened? -Why, you writing a book?
- Que s'est-il passé ? - Tu écris un livre ?
I'm going to propose a hypothesis.
Je vais proposer une hypothèse.
Last night, Raj accidentally made contact with an alien civilization...
Hier soir, Raj est entré en contact avec une civilisation extra—terrestre
...and has been ordered by the U.S. government to keep it a secret.
et le gouvernement lui a ordonné de garder le secret.
Nothing happened. Can we change the subject?
Il ne s‘est rien passé. On change de sujet ?
That sounds rehearsed. We are not alone.
Sa réponse a été répétée. On n‘est pas seuls.
HOWARD: Hey. SHELDON: Hello.
- Salut. - Bonjour.
Did you get to play with Raj's big telescope last night?
Tu as joué avec le gros télescope de Raj hier soir ?
-Where did that come from? -He never touched my telescope.
- Où as-tu pris ça ? - Il n‘a pas touché mon télescope.
-Way to go shutting up. -I did shut up. Now you shut up.
Tu aurais pu la fermer.
I can't believe you didn't call me this morning.
Tu aurais pu m‘appeler ce matin.
[English - us - an]
[French]